2A
+ Leader Election
+ Heartbeats

heartbeat = empty AppendEntry RPC
  leader assertions:
- single leader is elected
- new leader takes over iff old leader fails or if packets to/from old leader are lost

  store:
- state vars in Raft struct
- define new struct to hold info per log entry

  do RPC structs/func:
RequestVoteArgs RequestVoteReply
RequestVote() [handles RPC] so that servers will vote for one another

  Make: (timeout routine)
- add background goroutine to start leader election by sending RequestVote RPC when it hasn't heard from another peer for a while. thus learns who is leader or become as leader

  heartbeats:
- leader sends out empty AppendEntries RPCs periodically. write handler for this RPC that resets election timeout. heartbeat timeout -> new leader election (leaders stepping forward)
no timeout -> no peer steps forward as new leader





======= raft sketch (filtered for Part A)

STATE VARS
  general:
- phase		am I leader, follower or candidate?
- currentTerm	what I think the term is (0↑)
- votedFor	who I voted for *in current term* (null)

[general] RPC TERM SYNC (not required for 2A?)
  if currentTerm<term (RPC): currentTerm:=term; I am now follower

[follower] CANDIDACY TIMEOUT
  if timeout on receive AppendEntries OR grant vote: become candida.

[candidate] CALL ELECTION
  (init: start election)
  - currentTerm++
  - self-vote
  - reset election timer
  - send RequestVote to all
  - if majority: become leader
  - if AppendEntries RPC received: become follower
  - if election timeout: start new election

[leader] SENDS HEARTBEATS
  (init: send heartbeat to all)
  send heartbeat to all during idle periods // else sending data


== recipe
1.) add state vars to raft struct
> Raft		  struct ABC
  contains state vars
> GetState	  func	 A
  accesses state vars

2.) add vars to RequestVote structs (send and receive)
> RequestVoteArgs   struct AB	(sender RPC data)
> RequestVoteReply  struct A	(receiver RPC data)
// candidate election

3.) implement candidacy timeout + call election in Make()
> Make		  func	 ABC

4.) implement voting in RequestVote receiver
> RequestVote	  func	 AB	(receiver RPC handler)

// heartbeat
5.) add structs/funcs for ApplyEntries (heartbeat first)
> SendApplyEntries; ApplyEntries

6.) implement leader sending periodic heartbeats (<10/sec limit) (periodicity via time.Sleep())
> heartbeat func (triggered in goroutine in Make)

7.) add election timeout reset to ApplyEntries handler (desync them using rand package) (aim for 1 election round / sec; full election < 5 secs limit)
> ApplyEntries