========================

DATA CYCLE
1. client sends data to raft leader
2. leader *writes* and sends it to followers (RPC send)
3. followers write and acknowledge receipt (RPC receipt)
4. leader *commits* when majority acknowledge
5a. followers commit based on leader having committed
5b. leader *applies* (sends) to service

client >> raft >> service

========================

STATE VARIABLES
log[]	1-indexed. entries = {command, termWhenReceivedByLeader}
commitIndex	what I think is the highest committed entry [0↑]
lastApplied	highest applied (to service) entry [0↑]
 [leader variables (peer-indexed), reset on becoming leader]
nextIndex[]     next entry to send to peer [init: mLastEntry +1]
matchIndex[]	what I think is peer's highest replica. entry [0↑]

APPENDENTRIES VARIABLES
 send
prevLogIndex,prevLogTerm: sender's entry before payload,index+term
entries[]		  payload
leaderCommit	sender's commitIndex
 reply
success		= receiver had entry matching prevLogIndex,Term

=========================

 << order relations >> (between servers A,B)
A *dominates* B if the term of A is >= the term of B
A *leads* B if the commitIndex of A is >= the commitIndex of B

======================== Group per data cycle:

== IN
 Leader (Handles Start; follower immediately returns Start):
- data input:
  - append to my log (thereby increasing last entry index)


== WRITE
 Leader (Tracks):
- keep everyone updated: per follower
   if my last entry index >= nextIndex:
     send AppendEntries with payload = log[nextIndex:].
     ... the follower replies with success boolean:
     - true:
       nextIndex, matchIndex = myLastEntry+1
     - false:
       nextIndex--; retry

// matchIndex is ONLY updated upon AppendEntries success

 Follower (AppendEntries Receiver)
1. success := tS react &&
		receiver has entry matching prevLogIndex,Term
           (timeout auto-replies success=false)
2. merge log: (if success)
  a. delete my conflicted log entries:
    if my log vs payload: entry with different term at same index:
      delete log[entry:]
    // i.e. traverse myLog forward from prevLogIndex+1, stop when conflict encountered
  b. append new entries:
    append payload entries not already in log
    // i.e. find last myLog entry and append payload from there.


== COMMIT
 Leader (Tracks):
- commitIndex track:
   if exists N > commitIndex s.t.
     (A) majority matchIndex >= N && (B) log[N].term == my term
   then set commitIndex = N
  [implementation]
   linearly search indices from commitIndex+1 until A fails, testing B each time and memoing which is the largest term so far passing B.

 Follower (AppendEntries Receiver)
3. commitIndex sync:
   if sender strictly leads receiver, set commitIndex to min(leader's commitIndex, index of last payload entry)

// latter min argument is redundant bc always send latest writes? 


== OUT (APPLY)
 Everyone (Tracks):
- lastApplied track:
   if commitIndex > lastApplied:
    - log[lastApplied] -> applyCh
    - lastApplied++
- respond to caller: after entry applied


== VOTEREQUEST
add vote condition: candidate >= voter on the following:
  > log up-to-date order relation:
Raft determines which of two logs is more up-to-date by comparing the index and term of the last entries in the logs. If the logs have last entries with different terms, then the log with the later term is more up-to-date. If the logs end with the same term, then whichever log is longer is more up-to-date.
  [summary]
IF last entry terms differ: later last entry term log wins
ELSE: longer log wins
(equality iff same last term and same length)


[data cycle]
2. write
3. commit
4. out (apply)