APPENDENTRIES RPC:
 (heartbeat = empty AppendEntries)
S/R: Leader -> certain followers (heartbeat to all)
Purpose: Replicate log entries (heartbeat to delaying re-election)	
Handler:
 - reset election timeout + become follower
 - [data handling tbc]

REQUESTVOTE RPC:
S/R: Candidate -> Voter
Purpose: To gather votes for itself
Handler: reply with vote (in voteGranted): true iff
 - candidate term not ood
 - candidate's log extends voter's log
 - votedFor = null OR candidate

CONCEPTUAL PROCESSES:
- re-elections if follower doesn't receive AppendEntries from leader
- leader updates followers on log progress
- data phases: writing to log; committing to log; applying to svc.

STATE VARS
  general:
- phase		who am I? (leader, follower, candidate)
- currentTerm	what I think the term is (0↑)
- votedFor	who I voted for *in current term* (null)
- log[]		my log copy ({data; term when leader received it})
- commitIndex	index I think is latest logged
- lastApplied	index I think is latest applied
  leader:	[reinit after election]
- nextIndex	tracks peers: index of next log entry to send
- matchIndex	tracks peers: index of latest log entry peer has

GENERAL DOINGS
-   flushing data:
  if lastApplied<commitIndex: lastApplied++; apply log[lastApplied]
-   term sync [if my term is old, I should be follower]:
  if currentTerm<term (RPC): currentTerm:=term; I am now follower

FOLLOWER DOINGS
-   candidacy timeout:
reset IFF RPC receipt where sender is u-t-d (= RPC is "successful")
else become candidate

CANDIDATE DOINGS
-   candidate init:
  start election
-   start election:
  - currentTerm++
  - self-vote
  - reset election timer
  - send RequestVote to all
  - if majority: become leader
  - if AppendEntries RPC received: become follower
  - if election timeout: start new election

LEADER DOINGS
-   leader init:
  send heartbeat to all
-   still alive:
  send heartbeat to all during idle periods // else sending data
-   client requests:
  append requested entry to log
  responding upon applied entry
-   keeping followers updated:
  for followers if nextIndex[follower] <= commitIndex ("last log index"): send AppendEntries to follower with log[nextIndex:]
  if success: update nextIndex and matchIndex
  if fail (log inconsistency): nextIndex--; retry
-   commit to log:
  if exists N>commitIndex: matchIndex>=N (majority) AND log[N].term [currentTerm when the client request] == currentTerm [right now]: commitIndex := N [log[N] exists before commitIndex hits N].
-   (check how commitIndex is incremented by followers)

MISC NOTES
 all RPCs synchronise terms regardless of ulterior purpose
 I become leader if elected; I become follower if my term is ood OR if I receive AppendEntries
 currentTerm is stable if leader is successfully heartbeating
 voter votes for one server per term (caches it in votedFor)